<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>flopreynat.com</title>
    <link>https://flopreynat.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on flopreynat.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:51:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://flopreynat.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Logo design on the cheap</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2022-03-27-logo-design-on-the-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:51:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2022-03-27-logo-design-on-the-cheap/</guid>
      <description>Recently had to work on a website which needed a logo.
You clearly have 2 options:
 You ask a logo designer. This is a real job, people. If the success of your business is going to be largely impacted by your branding, then don&amp;rsquo;t be a fool and ask someone whose job is exactly this to do it for you. And pay her/him what she/he&amp;rsquo;s asking Your logo ain&amp;rsquo;t gonna make such a difference and you just want to get a logo on the cheap and are willing to do this yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Microsoft tracking with VS Codium</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2020-09-28-no-microsoft-tracking-vscodium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:51:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2020-09-28-no-microsoft-tracking-vscodium/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago, I switched from Sublime to VS Code, and never looked back. The code editor does everything I need, and having the terminal and console closed to your code is a mega plus.
But the other day, cyborg rights activist Aral Balkan, whom I was talking to on Twitter, mentioned to me the existence of VS Codium, a clone of Visual Studio Code, providing its users with the same Microsoft application experience, but without Microsoft’s telemetry code and data usage tracking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using git on your Synology</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2020-05-21-git-server-synology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2020-05-21-git-server-synology/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m pushing the majority of my git projects to github for the simple reason that 1. they are public and hence do not need to remain hidden from the rest of the world, and 2. they usually leverage open source technology which has been tweaked in some way and that could help others.
However, there are specific personal projects and notes I do version using git and that I do not wish to send to the likes of Github, Bitbucket, et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Gatsby</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2020-05-02-switching-to-gatsby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2020-05-02-switching-to-gatsby/</guid>
      <description>It had only been a month since I converted my site from Jekyll to Hugo. But with the quarantine and lockdown 😷 fully enforced, I took the time to dig even more the static-site-generator subject, and decided to dedicate some time to learn Gatsby, an open source framework based on React (which I knew very little about), and apply my newly-acquired skills to the redesign of this very site. Job now done ✅</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Hugo?</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2020-03-29-why-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 17:52:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2020-03-29-why-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Quick post to mention I switched my blog from Jekyll to Hugo.
Jekyll has been THE most popular static site generator since its creation back in 2008, and I naturally opted for it back in July 2015, as I was leaving Wordpress.
Back then, getting my hands into Jekyll had not been that easy, but using it past the installation phase had been a joy.
I was however keen to try Hugo, having heard a lot of good things about it, especially since it was branded as the world’s fastest framework for building websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I keep on improving my Data Privacy in 2020</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2020-02-23-data-privacy-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 10:33:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2020-02-23-data-privacy-2020/</guid>
      <description>Data privacy has been a hot subject even before GDPR (25 May 2018) and CCPA (1st January 2020) became officially applicable.
I actually discussed this very subject early 2017, discussing the various open source tools I opted for at the time.
Anyway, 2 years on, let&amp;rsquo;s make a quick assessment of what was succesful and kept as well as look into the other tools I am currently using to ensure my data pricacy is in great shape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spin up php server locally with Docker</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2019-12-26-php-server-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2019-12-26-php-server-docker/</guid>
      <description>Almost same use case and files than last time. But this time, using Docker, which I had been wanting to test out for so long.
docker run -p 80:80 -v /Users/your-username/path-to-docker-folder/src/:/var/www/html/ hello-world Everything is brilliantly explained on this Learn Docker in 12 Minutes video.
Like on last post, proof files here.
So long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spin up php server locally in no time</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2019-12-01-php-server-spin-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2019-12-01-php-server-spin-easy/</guid>
      <description>Another post on tooling with this time a quick and easy way to locally spin up a php server, for - say - php templating and testing.
php -S localhost:2222 As mentioned here, the CLI SAPI provides a built-in web server (as of PHP 5.4.0).
It is not intended to be a full-featured web server. But designed to aid application development.
Using the above command line is pretty much all is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crop documents with Mac&#39;s Preview</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2019-10-06-crop-documents-mac-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2019-10-06-crop-documents-mac-preview/</guid>
      <description>So you want to quickly/cheaply crop a jpg or pdf but have no tools lying around your mac to do so. There&amp;rsquo;s actually an easy way to do it using Mac&amp;rsquo;s native image and PDF viewer Preview.
 Command + K
 Really handy way if you can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered installing gimp, or alternative.
 Open the file in Preview Select Tools &amp;gt; Rectangular Selection Draw your selection area on the file Use Command + K to crop the image Save your document  So long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick way to run a windows application on a mac</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2019-08-02-quick-way-run-windows-application-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2019-08-02-quick-way-run-windows-application-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>From time to time, as a mac owner, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to run a Windows application for testing (or other) purposes.
Obviously, there are tons of solutions allowing you to run windows on a mac, but not all are light, free and quick wins.
 VIRTUALIZATION TIME
 The quickest and easisest way (to me) is to use Virtualbox (open source and free), download a free virtual Windows machine from the Microsoft developer website, and spin it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macbook Pro boot up issue with no startup chime... WTF</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2019-02-16-macbook-pro-boot-up-issue-no-startup-chime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2019-02-16-macbook-pro-boot-up-issue-no-startup-chime/</guid>
      <description>Already talked about this issue once&amp;hellip; here, except this time I don&amp;rsquo;t have the chance to hear the startup chime, nor to reset any PRAM, nothing.
The only chance I get is to enter my password and see the apple screen get stuck for ever.
 SAFE MODE
 Once I enter my password, the only thing I can do is press on the SHIFT key and hold it, until I enter the Safe mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github: 2FA and personal token</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2018-03-23-github-2fa-commandline/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2018-03-23-github-2fa-commandline/</guid>
      <description>So you&amp;rsquo;ve decided to turn on two-factor authentication (as you do) for your github account and you can&amp;rsquo;t commit (anymore) to your repos using the command line.
TL;DR
Create a personal token.
You won&amp;rsquo;t be asked to provide a 2FA code when authenticating to GitHub on the command line using HTTPS URLs. Instead, you must create a personal access token and use its as a password.
 Log into your account Click on your avatar, then Settings Click on Developer Settings Choose Personal access tokens Generate new token Give your token a name Select the scope and permissions of your token Use your token as your password when prompted in the terminal  Done ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fontawesome Alfred Workflow</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2018-01-01-fontawesome-alfred-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2018-01-01-fontawesome-alfred-workflow/</guid>
      <description>You have Alfred and use it on a regular basis? Your job is to build websites, or simple protoypes? You&amp;rsquo;re a fan of Font Awesome?  Then you can leverage the power of Alfred&amp;rsquo;s Workflow and use it on the fly when including font awesome parameters into your designs.
Simply donwload Alfred&amp;rsquo;s Font Awesome worklfow, and you&amp;rsquo;re good to go.
Invoke the use of Alfred while designing (usually with &amp;lsquo;ALT+ENTER&amp;rsquo;), type fa and search through the available icons, pick one and click &amp;lsquo;ENTER&amp;rsquo;, your class is in your design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No camera was found</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2017-05-31-camera-not-detected-hangout/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2017-05-31-camera-not-detected-hangout/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re most likely running on Mavericks, or El Capitan, are using your mac or a monitor with integrated camera, and keep on getting something along the lines of &amp;rsquo;no camera was found&amp;rsquo; messages from Hangout or other web conferencing apps.
Issue happened to me on dozens of times with an Apple Thunderbolt.
This post isn&amp;rsquo;t intended to get to the bottom of this issue. So you can put back the screwdrivers where they belong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive email design framework MJML to the test</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2017-05-16-responsive-email-design-framework-mjml/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2017-05-16-responsive-email-design-framework-mjml/</guid>
      <description>Email design is a real pain in the arse. We all know that. Therefore I decided to give mjml a go. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know of mjml.io, it&amp;rsquo;s a responsive email design framework built by a team of developers at Mailjet, a competitor of Mailchimp.
The beauty of this framework results in the fact that you create something very much close to html, using an MJML markup language, and as mentioned in its detailed documentation, &amp;ldquo;its semantic syntax makes it easy and straightforward and its rich standard components library speeds up your development time and lightens your email codebase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DuckDuckGo hacks for developers</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2017-04-18-duckduckgo-hacks-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2017-04-18-duckduckgo-hacks-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>DuckDuckGo is by far the best search engine out there. For your own privacy for starters, and also as a great little tool for us dev folks, adept of quick tech &amp;amp; code answers, and geeky little features.
 Smarter Search!
 A few tips and tricks that you may not know of. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using some for few for months, and only discovered others in the last few days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Data Privacy: start off 2017 on the right foot</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2017-01-03-personal-data-privacy-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2017-01-03-personal-data-privacy-2017/</guid>
      <description>New year new start. What a great opportunity to start it off on the right foot and greatly improve your behaviour and overall awareness on the personal data privacy subject. You will feel great and you will start breaking the chain!
As discussed last time we talked on the matter, our personal data privacy matters a lot, and yet, it is being violated more and more.
A quick glimpse at the news tell us the UK and Theresa May are trying to pass a law that will make it obligatory for internet providers to store every user’s history for up to a year (although the text has just been declared unlawful by EU&amp;rsquo;s Highest Court), or the German secret services are allegedly wanting to decrypt messengers like WhatsApp via the ANISKI project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a PDF Compress Automator App</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-12-20-pdf-compress-automator-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-12-20-pdf-compress-automator-app/</guid>
      <description>Every time I want to compress pdfs on a new apple machine, I find myself looking for the same (great) posts on the subject, and rarely find the one I&amp;rsquo;m looking for.
This is why I&amp;rsquo;m putting up this nice (personal) go-to blog post on how to easily and quickly set up a PDF Compress Automator App, as I use the app almost every day.
 small is beautiful
 Right so, the steps are as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Our Personal) Data Privacy Matters</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-11-17-data-privacy-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-11-17-data-privacy-series/</guid>
      <description>(Our personal) Data Privacy is a big deal. If you, like me, get annoyed every time you receive an unwanted newsletter, or feel wary about looking up some specific items while logged in on google, you&amp;rsquo;ll know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about.
This subject has always been of great interest to me, both from personal and technoligcal stand points. And as time passes by, and I see new generations of youngsters come into play, with absolutely no experience of what the time without the internet could have looked/felt like, it gets me thinking more and more about this situation, which I know isn&amp;rsquo;t new, but is not getting any better to say the least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed up your Salesforce admin search with Sid&#39;s Searchbox</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-10-12-salesforce-admin-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-10-12-salesforce-admin-search/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re a Salesforce user, especially a developer or admin, you may spend most of your day in the Salesforce setup area, adding and editing apex classes, visualforce pages and adjusting other admin settings.
Anything helping you stop wasting time on the setup area is more than welcome. Therefore I can only recommend you to give this chrome extension a go.
 In Search of Speed
 Made by Salesforce MVP and Dreamforce 16 superstar ;) Sid Nagavarapu, Salesforce Searchbox is a great way to gain in productivity by adding to all config pages a simple search box, which will search in all configuration items on the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSI and vertical mouse: a look back at the last 6 months</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-09-21-rsi-vertical-mouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-09-21-rsi-vertical-mouse/</guid>
      <description>Repetitive strain injury (RSI) is a frequent issue when you spend 10+ hours a day in front of a computer, and it is something I have unfortunately been experiencing these last few years.
Since I own a mac, I have always been using a magic mouse, but as aching in my right hand (and arm) started to occur on a more regular basis, I started wondering whether this beautiful, yet - let&amp;rsquo;s be honest - way too small device was the root of my problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress staging environments on the cheap</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-08-30-wordpress-staging-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-08-30-wordpress-staging-environment/</guid>
      <description>Staging environments are one of the keys of a (proper and) controlled deployment process, whatever the technology. Wordpress isn&amp;rsquo;t any different.
You have a problem if you - like me - run a few things on wordpress, don&amp;rsquo;t consider it as a priority subject (hence do not have the time, nor the money to commit on the suject), &amp;hellip;yet still want to make it a decent process.
Typical &amp;ldquo;have it both ways&amp;rdquo; conundrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a dribbble API-powered portfolio in no time</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-07-04-dribbble-api-portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-07-04-dribbble-api-portfolio/</guid>
      <description>APIs are a foundational element in today&amp;rsquo;s tech world. They help you enrich your data, and remain the best, simplest and quickest way to integrate to other engines, apps &amp;hellip; you name it.
In this example, we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on a quick (and dirty) dribble to website integration, helping you generate a dribbble-api-powered portfolio, and kill two birds with one stone.
 Leveraging APIs Matters
 Quick codepen showing you in details how I did it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac Finder freezes... WTF</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-05-29-mac-finder-freezes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-05-29-mac-finder-freezes/</guid>
      <description>Another blog post on Apple devices playing up (following the &amp;ldquo;boot to black screen&amp;rdquo; one) with this time, the way to resolve a frozen finder on OSX (Mavericks in my case).
The thing happened to me a few months back, with Finder freezing over and over after a few seconds or minutes of usage, forcing me to force quit Finder on numerous occasions throughout the day.
Fed up with this bug, and not willing to move away from the native file managing app, I eventually got it sorted out by simply using Mac&amp;rsquo;s Safe Mode, something that Windows users might be more inclined to be using on a regular basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gulp throws Potentially unhandled rejection error</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-04-27-gulp-throws-potentially-unhandled-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-04-27-gulp-throws-potentially-unhandled-rejection/</guid>
      <description>So you&amp;rsquo;re using Gulp and you&amp;rsquo;re thrown a &amp;ldquo;Potentially unhandled rejection [2] Error: no writecb&amp;rdquo; and you have no idea what to do next&amp;hellip;
It was my case up to last night when running Gulp for the first time (I usually run Grunt) during the initialization of Wes Bos&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;React for Beginners&amp;rdquo;, and the run of a gulp-stylus task.
 Updates first
 Initial reaction should be to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re up to date with all components at hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alfred App Review</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-03-30-alfred-app-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-03-30-alfred-app-review/</guid>
      <description>An app all windows users envy us if they have had the chance to take Mac&amp;rsquo;s already-powerful search feature to the next level, with Alfred - the award winning app and best butler I have ever known&amp;hellip;
Like any developer out there, I want to use the keyboard as much as I can. For productivity reasons first, and for others.
Been using Alfred for years, and I can&amp;rsquo;t get bored of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leverage Sublime Text Macros to automate repeatable actions</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-03-30-leverage-sublime-macros-to-automate-repeatable-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-03-30-leverage-sublime-macros-to-automate-repeatable-actions/</guid>
      <description>Sublime Text Macros are a smart little tool to automate repeatable (and often-repeated) patterns.
For example, I need to build arrays from lists of things on a regular basis. As easy as it can be in sublime to perform such an operation, using the basic automation provided by Macros is the best way forward.
 Automation, automation, automation
 Simply navigate to Tools/Record Macro to record what you want Sublime to do on your behalf, Save your macro with a &amp;lsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grunt throws a Maximum call stack size exceeded error</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-01-27-gruntjs-maximum-call-stack-size-exceeded-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-01-27-gruntjs-maximum-call-stack-size-exceeded-error/</guid>
      <description>Grunt throws a &amp;lsquo;maximum call stack size exceeded&amp;rsquo; error after running a simple task, and you haven&amp;rsquo;t got the slightest idea what it means. No sweat.
But I can&amp;rsquo;t blame as this is just what happened to me today while working on a website redesign. The grunt task is a simple &amp;lsquo;imagemin&amp;rsquo; task I decided to run separately, and I don&amp;rsquo;t recall having had the same issue before.
Cut a long story short, you launch something along the lines of: &amp;ldquo;grunt imagemin&amp;rdquo; in your terminal, and you&amp;rsquo;re thrown the following error:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Record your screen in animated GIF format with Licecap</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-01-07-record-screen-animated-gif/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-01-07-record-screen-animated-gif/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m often being asked what screen recorder software I use, since I frequently document tutorials, emails, and other user guides with self-explanatory gifs.
And since the app I use is 1. open source (hence free), 2. super light, and 3. very easy to use, I thought I would give Licecap the credit it deserves.
As mentioned on the app&amp;rsquo;s website, Licecap is a simple animated screen captures software. It probably has the least sexy logo ever, but the app is just great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autocomplete file names in Sublime</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-01-06-autocomplete-file-names-sublimetext/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2016-01-06-autocomplete-file-names-sublimetext/</guid>
      <description>Another cool add-on to your Sublime with this great little plugin that allows you to autocomple your file names and speed up your coding.
Use your Package Control (CMD + SHIFT + P) to install AutoFileName and start playing with it.
 Autocomplete FTW!
 Been using for a long time now, but I reckon it hasn&amp;rsquo;t got the fame it deserves.
Kudos to @boundincode (Liam Cain), the creator behind AutoFileName.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macbook Pro boots to black screen... WTF</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-12-23-macbook-pro-boots-to-black-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-12-23-macbook-pro-boots-to-black-screen/</guid>
      <description>So you boot your macbook pro, and you get&amp;hellip; well not much. A black screen staring back at you while you frantically reach for your phone to check possible solutions to this problem.
PRAM Reset Look no further. The thing just happened to me and I managed to get through it by resetting the machine&amp;rsquo;s PRAM, which is - apparently - a common troubleshooting technique when your favorite apple goes to f***.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move and resize windows with Spectacle</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-12-18-move-and-resize-windows-with-spectacle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-12-18-move-and-resize-windows-with-spectacle/</guid>
      <description>Repositioning and resizing windows isn’t probably the most entertaining subject out there, but as we do those two all day long, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it once and for all.
I remember having blogged about this subject on another blog about 3 years ago, and today, I&amp;rsquo;m finding myself talking about this very same subject to various mac users (since it&amp;rsquo;s a native feature on windows), having failed to deal with the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Sublime Text Shortcuts CheatSheet</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-10-27-sublime-text-shortcuts-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-10-27-sublime-text-shortcuts-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Have you documented your own Sublime Text shortcut cheatsheet?&amp;rsquo; is a question I never get asked. But despite all your efforts to avoid the subject, here it is. In your face!
This post is likely to get updated on a regular basis since I tend to learn new stuff every day. See, when you start low, you&amp;rsquo;re bound to progress more often than never :)
So we&amp;rsquo;ve already spoken about ST3&amp;rsquo;s clipboard history capability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Authenticator is producing the wrong codes</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-09-30-google-authenticator-producing-wrong-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-09-30-google-authenticator-producing-wrong-code/</guid>
      <description>What do you do when your Google Authenticator produces the wrong codes, and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing much you can do about it?
I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of the two-factor authentification, the now famous user identification system by means of the combination of two different components. It usually involves a password and some kind of time-based token available via an app on a mobile phone.
 2-step verification is officially the best thing since sliced bread</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive video code snippet</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-09-15-responsive-video-code-snippet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-09-15-responsive-video-code-snippet/</guid>
      <description>An ancient blogpost of mine, and this clever responsive video code snippet presented (at the time) by Ethan Marcotte, at btconf 2014 during his Laziness In The Time Of Responsive Design talk.
A quick way to make videos look good at any size, the height/width ratio of the media now respected.
Enough chit chat.
.video-container { position: relative; height: 0; padding-bottom: 56.25%; } .video-container &amp;gt; * { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; height: 100%; width: 100%; } There’s a codepen for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Google Charts Responsive</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-09-08-make-google-charts-responsive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-09-08-make-google-charts-responsive/</guid>
      <description>A quick blog post on how to make Google Charts play nicely in responsive mode. Nothing close to rocket science but still useful.
For those who don’t know, Google Charts is a visualization tool, a gallery of interactive charts and data tools that you can integrate into your website. You provide data through php, json and Google Charts display it nicely for you.
Issue By default, the charts come in the form of fixed width element which you can easily tweak to adapt to the now-famous ‘width:100%’ format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Jekyll plugins on Github</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-08-25-jekyll-plugins-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-08-25-jekyll-plugins-github/</guid>
      <description>A bit of reading for all jekyll newbies who, like me, decided to host their Jekyll site on Github pages (or are in the process to do so), and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be aware of the limitations around the subject.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been running this site on Jekyll for a few weeks only, and making discoveries along the way. When I decided to install and use the first of many plugins available, I hit the wall and quickly realised the topic was far from an easy affair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sublime Text 3 Clipboard History</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-08-18-sublimetext-clipboard-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-08-18-sublimetext-clipboard-history/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently moved to Sublime Text 3, having enjoyed several years of cruising on version 2. The latest version is now more than mature (hence my move) and has additional features ST2 was short of. The ability to browse through your clipboard history is defo one of them.
 ⌘ + K then ⌘ + V
 It&amp;rsquo;s as simple as that, just go ⌘ + K before hitting your usual ⌘ + V and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to pick from your latest clipboard entries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Disqus comments to Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-08-14-adding-disqus-comments-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-08-14-adding-disqus-comments-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Adding comments via Disqus to your Jekyll blog is something you probably want to do if you want a bit of life and interaction. Good news: it couldn&amp;rsquo;t be easier.
There are installation instructions on the Disqus documentation, and on various places around the web, but I thought I would recap the lot for y&amp;rsquo;all.
 &amp;ldquo;Great discussions are happening here&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; so Disqus says. Unless nothing much will in fact happen, and you&amp;rsquo;re fine with this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll contact form with Formspree</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-08-10-jekyll-contact-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-08-10-jekyll-contact-form/</guid>
      <description>So you got yourself a nice static site, and you want to give your audience a chance to talk to you (directly) with a simple contact form, something you might be used to having used wordpress, php, and a database.
Except there ain&amp;rsquo;t no database here. Even less php back end. Hence you&amp;rsquo;ve got to rely on other ways to get personal messages sent to you.
Formspree - Functional HTML forms When I stumbled upon Formspree, it did look like the perfect match.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free stock photos for your projects</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-08-06-free-stock-photos-that-dont-suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-08-06-free-stock-photos-that-dont-suck/</guid>
      <description>Just a go-to blog post (for myself really) when on the lookout for free stock photos (that don&amp;rsquo;t suck) for your web design projects, print needs et al.
A lot of good and excellent sites for you to pick exceptionnally-pro-looking pics from&amp;hellip; Here we go.
The ones I&amp;rsquo;ve used from the start:
 Death to the Stock Photo Unsplash especially since Arthur Weill released a little search engine for Unsplash.  &amp;hellip;and the rest of them, in alphabetical order:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error installing jekyll: Failed to build gem native extension</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-07-29-jekyll-failed-to-build-gem-native-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-07-29-jekyll-failed-to-build-gem-native-extension/</guid>
      <description>Though I would post this one since I did experience a few issues attempting to install jekyll, including this &amp;ldquo;Failed to build gem native extension&amp;rdquo; annoying error.
Right, so you have it all installed. So you think. As advised on the jekyll site, you’ve done your:
sudo gem update --system Xcode and its command line tools are in there, but you still get an error while running:
sudo gem install jekyll something like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Jekyll?</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-07-22-why-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2015-07-22-why-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve got it easy on that one. Site is brand new, hence built from scratch, with absolutely no data to migrate/integrate. Picking a technology like Jekyll to build and run this new personal pad was therefore an easy choice to make.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Wordpress (most times) and Perch (a few times) to create most of my personal/client/others&amp;rsquo; websites, and despite having nagged a few times about performance or bloated code, it was most of the time down to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Images Meetup: Coming together is a beginning</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2013-09-13-responsive-images-meetup-coming-together-is-a-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2013-09-13-responsive-images-meetup-coming-together-is-a-beginning/</guid>
      <description>Last time I talked about responsive images, I did mention I was due to go to the responsive images meetup in Paris, and as the long-awaited event happened a couple of days ago, I thought it would be nice to write a quick recap for the folks unable to make it.
SIDE NOTE Before we get to the the nitty gritty, let me start this blog post with a quick line on the venue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add a neat little breakpoint snippet to your Sublime</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2013-05-15-sublime-breakpoint-snippet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/posts/2013-05-15-sublime-breakpoint-snippet/</guid>
      <description>Let’s get Sassy today with this little yet very useful Sublime Text 2 breakpoint snippet handmade by James Nowland and obviously editable as you wish.
If, like me, you code a lot of responsive sites, chances are that you work with Sass and end up putting half a million @include breakpoint lines, working your site’s scss the modular way… as you do.
Well, this little snippet will surely reduce your work, by allowing you to tabTrigger mq (or whatever you wanna call it) into the full @include breakpoint desired code lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is flo.
I work in Customer Success at Odaseva, a young and brilliant company providing Enterprise-class Data Governance for Salesforce customers. If your company uses Salesforce, there&amp;rsquo;s a strong chance you&amp;rsquo;ll be needing a solution for Data Protection, Data Privacy, or Data Agility at some point so do not hesitate and check us out.
I have been building websites (on both private and professionnal fronts) for more than 15 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://flopreynat.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flopreynat.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Want to talk about code, mentorship, and more?
Ping me on Twitter via @flopreynat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
