<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>flopreynat.com</title>
    <description>website for flopreynat</description>
    <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.flopreynat.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 21:55:43 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 21:55:43 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Data Privacy Matters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Data Privacy is a big deal. If you, like me, get annoyed every time you receive an unwanted newsletter, or feel wary about looking up some specific items while logged in on google, you’ll know what I’m talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This subject has always been of great interest to me, both from personal and technoligcal stand points.
And as time passes by, and I see new generations of youngsters come into play, with absolutely no experience of what the time without the internet could have looked/felt like, it gets me thinking more and more about this situation, which I know isn’t new, but is not getting any better to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the reason why I am launching today with this quick post a series of articles on the subject.
I have made drastic changes in my personal life theses last few weeks, and this blog is a great way to keep the words of advice from all savvy people resonate, and share my actions and overall experience in improving my personal data privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with a cool prez from &lt;a href=&quot;https://ar.al/&quot;&gt;“Aral Balkan”&lt;/a&gt; who’s taken his ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://ind.ie/beyond-the-clouds/&quot;&gt;“Beyond The Clouds”&lt;/a&gt;’ prez to another level with ‘The Matrix, Inverted’, a great talk on people faming made in Malmö, at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://oredev.org/&quot;&gt;“Øredev Conference”&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If it’s free, YOU are the product&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For your info, I have been following Aral’s work for a few years now. Aral is big on Human Rights, Social Justice &amp;amp; Ethical Design, and runs &lt;a href=&quot;https://ind.ie/&quot;&gt;“ind.ie”&lt;/a&gt;, a small social enterprise striving for social justice in the digital age.
His eloquence and passion for defending data privacy are second to none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the wise words!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/190855745&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/190855745&quot;&gt;The Matrix, Inverted&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/user4280938&quot;&gt;&amp;Oslash;redev Conference&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/data-privacy-matters.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/data-privacy-matters.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Speed up your Salesforce admin search with Sid&#39;s Searchbox</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re a Salesforce user, especially a developer or admin, you may spend most of your day in the Salesforce setup area, adding and editing apex classes, visualforce pages and adjusting other admin settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything helping you stop wasting time on the setup area is more than welcome. Therefore I can only recommend you to give this chrome extension a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In Search of Speed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Made by Salesforce MVP and Dreamforce 16 superstar ;) Sid Nagavarapu, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/salesforce-searchbox/moaokcjghnjifeeahifofckbmhofjdbi&quot;&gt;“Salesforce Searchbox”&lt;/a&gt; is a great way to gain in productivity by adding to all config pages a simple search box, which will search in all configuration items on the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/salesforce-admin-search-account.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;salesforce search admin&quot; title=&quot;salesforce search admin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plugin supports some basic regex searches if you want to go fancy. In any case, you’ll speed up your searches and will defo spend more time providing the most value to the CRM users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/salesforce-admin-search.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/salesforce-admin-search.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>salesforce</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RSI and vertical mouse: a look back at the last 6 months</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Repetitive strain injury (RSI) is a frequent issue when you spend 10+ hours a day in front of a computer, and it is something I have unfortunately been experiencing these last few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I own a mac, I have always been using a magic mouse, but as aching in my right hand (and arm) started to occur on a more regular basis, I started wondering whether this beautiful, yet - let’s be honest - way too small device was the root of my problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;DANGER MOUSE !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discussing the matter with my osteopath quickly led to the option of using a vertical mouse, helping you  keep your hand in a natural position. This is why I moved to ‘verticality’ 6 months ago, with the purchase of a basic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.fr/gp/product/B00D84P8O8/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o07_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;“usb vertical mouse ZeleSouris”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few reasons why I picked this low-budget mouse:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;this was going to be more like a pilot phase (so I thought)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;non-wireless mice are less heavy (no batteries), hence easier to move&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;this specific device was not pricy hence more than worth a shot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 months on and I have to admit this was the best choice ever. Getting used to it took only a few days as far as I was concerned. I doubt the mouse I picked is the best ever, but my RSI has gone for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can only advise you to ditch the good looks of the magic mouse for an old bulky mouse, a trackpad or a vertical mouse, should you suffer (or wish to prevent) from RSI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/rsi-vertical-mouse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/rsi-vertical-mouse.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>uncategorized</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wordpress staging environments on the cheap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Staging environments are one of the keys of a (proper and) controlled deployment process, whatever the technology. Wordpress isn’t any different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have a problem if you - like me - run a few things on wordpress, don’t consider it as a priority subject (hence do not have the time, nor the money to commit on the suject), …yet still want to make it a decent process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typical “have it both ways” conundrum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;DEV &amp;gt; STAGING ENVIRONMENT &amp;gt; PRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here are a few options, my views on them, and eventually a decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professional Wordpress hosting (Paid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best option is to get people (or an app) meant to do this for you. Defo the best option if this subject is top priority for you. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wpengine.com/support/staging/&quot;&gt;“WPEngine”&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://mediatemple.net/community/products/wordpress/204645480/staging-sites-for-your-wordpress-hosting-service&quot;&gt;“Media Temple”&lt;/a&gt; come to mind to name only a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WP Migrate DB Pro (Paid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A popular plugin, often praised on &lt;a href=&quot;http://shoptalkshow.com/&quot;&gt;“ShopTalk Show”&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://deliciousbrains.com/wp-migrate-db-pro/pricing/&quot;&gt;“WP Migrate DB Pro”&lt;/a&gt; is a great option to get your wordpress sites in sync (all content including media) with one click. Cool option to implement a push to production process. Starting at 89 box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: I ain’t being sponsored for any of those paid options.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, I can’t be investigating any resource in this subject. Yet, I want to be able to set up a few environments and sync content and settings in an easy (and quick process), without having to deal with media url issues (cough wordpress import cough).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me emphasize on the repeatable process here since I really want to be able to do more than the usual local wp-cloud wp sync’ing. Testing things as they live on the web has got to be a pre-requisite. Things happen differently when not happening on local machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, went with…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All-in-One WP Migration (Free)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As advertised, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/all-in-one-wp-migration/&quot;&gt;“the plugin”&lt;/a&gt; allows you to export your database, media files, plugins, and themes. You can apply unlimited find/replace operations on your database and the plugin will also fix any serialization problems that occur during find/replace operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not bad for a free option, and works like a charm to get those wordpress environments in sync.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/wordpress-staging-environment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/wordpress-staging-environment.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>wordpress</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Create a dribbble API-powered portfolio in no time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;APIs are a foundational element in today’s tech world. They help you enrich your data, and remain the best, simplest and quickest way to integrate to other engines, apps … you name it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example, we’ll focus on a quick (and dirty) dribble to website integration, helping you generate a dribbble-api-powered portfolio, and kill two birds with one stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Leveraging APIs Matters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick (code)pen below showing you in details how I did it.
Do not be too judgemental on the overall design, this was made in a few minutes, throwing bootstrap on a page before connecting to my dribbble account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The longest part was to register an application on your dribbble account. Simply log into your account, navigate to Account Settings &amp;gt; Applications, and register your app. You’ll be needing your Client Access Token to make this work…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;265&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;0&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;oLgyZQ&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;js,result&quot; data-user=&quot;flopreynat&quot; data-embed-version=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/flopreynat/pen/oLgyZQ/&quot;&gt;dribbble portfolio with dribbble api v1&lt;/a&gt; by flo preynat (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/flopreynat&quot;&gt;@flopreynat&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/dribbble-api-portfolio.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/dribbble-api-portfolio.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mac Finder freezes... WTF</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Another blog post on Apple devices playing up (following the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flopreynat.com/blog/macbook-pro-boots-to-black-screen.html&quot;&gt;“boot to black screen”&lt;/a&gt; one) with this time, the way to resolve a frozen finder on OSX (Mavericks in my case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing happened to me a few months back, with Finder freezing over and over after a few seconds or minutes of usage, forcing me to force quit Finder on numerous occasions throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fed up with this bug, and not willing to move away from the native file managing app, I eventually got it sorted out by simply using Mac’s Safe Mode, something that Windows users might be more inclined to be using on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Safe Mode baby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personnally had never used the safe mode before, despite around 10 years on apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you have a frozen Finder, go for it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow these steps to start up into safe mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start or restart your Mac.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Immediately after you hear the startup sound, press and hold the Shift key.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release the Shift key when you see the Apple logo appear on the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Apple logo appears, it might take longer than usual to reach the login screen or your desktop. This is because your Mac performs a directory check of your startup disk as part of safe mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To leave safe mode, restart your computer without pressing any keys during startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201262&quot;&gt;“Apple Support website”&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/mac-finder-freezes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/mac-finder-freezes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gulp throws Potentially unhandled rejection error</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So you’re using Gulp and you’re thrown a “Potentially unhandled rejection [2] Error: no writecb” and you have no idea what to do next…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my case up to last night when running Gulp for the first time (I usually run Grunt) during the initialization of &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactforbeginners.com/&quot;&gt;Wes Bos’ “React for Beginners”&lt;/a&gt;, and the run of a gulp-stylus task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Updates first&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial reaction should be to make sure you’re up to date with all components at hand. All modules being all on their latest versions, let’s turn to node.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick check shows an outdated version, let’s get this updated. Here’s how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot;&gt;
(sudo) npm cache clean -f
(sudo) npm install -g n
(sudo) n stable
node -v
v6.0.0
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try running gulp again. Error should have gone…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/gulp-throws-potentially-unhandled-rejection-no-writecb.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/gulp-throws-potentially-unhandled-rejection-no-writecb.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>gulp</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Alfred App Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An app all windows users envy us if they have had the chance to take Mac’s already-powerful search feature to the next level, with Alfred - the award winning app and best butler I have ever known…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any developer out there, I want to use the keyboard as much as I can. For productivity reasons first, and for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Been using Alfred for years, and I can’t get bored of it. Don’t look at this post like an expert article on the subject, I have not even purchased the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alfredapp.com/powerpack/buy/&quot;&gt;Powerpack&lt;/a&gt;, feature unlocking the likes of workflows, integrations, and even remote control to your IOS devices.
To be totally honest, I have never really looked into the Powerpack, but I may be tempted to leverage their integration with Asana, another must-have IMHO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It serves me right!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, for now, I use Alfred the most simple way ever, but it just works for me. Here are a few things you can do with Alfred:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quickly find a file by typing “find” + the name of the file&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launch any app without using the mouse&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;calculate anything quickly by just typing numbers and operations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launch a search on any site (eg. google, twitter, youtube etc)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launch a google image search&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look up a place on Maps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quit all apps at the end of the working day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Empty the recycle bin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;etc…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily configure your shortcuts and have for example “google” shortened to “g” (just an example).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, I love this app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alfredapp.com/&quot;&gt;Alfred 2 for Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/alfred-app-review.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/alfred-app-review.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>apps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Leverage Sublime Text Macros to automate repeatable actions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sublime Text Macros are a smart little tool to automate repeatable (and often-repeated) patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I need to build arrays from lists of things on a regular basis. As easy as it can be in sublime to perform such an operation, using the basic automation provided by Macros is the best way forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Automation, automation, automation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply navigate to Tools/Record Macro to record what you want Sublime to do on your behalf, Save your macro with a ‘.sublime-macro’ extension and replay it as much as you need to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://flopreynat.com/img/sublime-text-macros.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Sublime Text Macros&quot; title=&quot;Sublime Text macros&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/leverage-sublime-macros-to-automate-repeatable-actions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/leverage-sublime-macros-to-automate-repeatable-actions.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sublime</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Grunt throws a Maximum call stack size exceeded error</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Grunt throws a ‘maximum call stack size exceeded’ error after running a simple task, and you haven’t got the slightest idea what it means. No sweat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I can’t blame as this is just what happened to me today while working on a website redesign. The grunt task is a simple ‘imagemin’ task I decided to run separately, and I don’t recall having had the same issue before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut a long story short, you launch something along the lines of:
“grunt imagemin” in your terminal, and you’re thrown the following error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;RangeError: Maximum call stack size exceeded&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don’t name your task aliases like your tasks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not find the issue in Grunt’s documentation as, ironically, it’s not the first hit on google serach results, but it’s in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can not name your tasks like the task itself, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gruntjs.com/frequently-asked-questions#why-am-i-getting-a-maximum-call-stack-size-exceeded-error&quot;&gt;as detailed here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I went from 
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;grunt.registerTask(“imagemin”, [“imagemin”]);&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;grunt.registerTask(“imageminifier”, [“imagemin”]);&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… and it worked like a charm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/gruntjs-maximum-call-stack-size-exceeded-error.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/gruntjs-maximum-call-stack-size-exceeded-error.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>gruntjs</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
