<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>flopreynat.com</title>
    <description>website for flopreynat</description>
    <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.flopreynat.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 22:32:28 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 22:32:28 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Leverage Sublime Text Macros to automate repeatable actions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sublime Text Macros are a smart little tool to automate repeatable (and often-repeated) patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I need to build arrays from lists of things on a regular basis. As easy as it can be in sublime to perform such an operation, using the basic automation provided by Macros is the best way forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Automation, automation, automation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply navigate to Tools/Record Macro to record what you want Sublime to do on your behalf, Save your macro with a ‘.sublime-macro’ extension and replay it as much as you need to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://flopreynat.com/img/sublime-text-macros.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Sublime Text Macros&quot; title=&quot;Sublime Text macros&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/leverage-sublime-macros-to-automate-repeatable-actions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/leverage-sublime-macros-to-automate-repeatable-actions.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sublime</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Grunt throws a Maximum call stack size exceeded error</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Grunt throws a ‘maximum call stack size exceeded’ error after running a simple task, and you haven’t got the slightest idea what it means. No sweat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I can’t blame as this is just what happened to me today while working on a website redesign. The grunt task is a simple ‘imagemin’ task I decided to run separately, and I don’t recall having had the same issue before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut a long story short, you launch something along the lines of:
“grunt imagemin” in your terminal, and you’re thrown the following error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;RangeError: Maximum call stack size exceeded&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don’t name your task aliases like your tasks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not find the issue in Grunt’s documentation as, ironically, it’s not the first hit on google serach results, but it’s in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can not name your tasks like the task itself, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gruntjs.com/frequently-asked-questions#why-am-i-getting-a-maximum-call-stack-size-exceeded-error&quot;&gt;as detailed here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I went from 
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;grunt.registerTask(“imagemin”, [“imagemin”]);&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;grunt.registerTask(“imageminifier”, [“imagemin”]);&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… and it worked like a charm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/gruntjs-maximum-call-stack-size-exceeded-error.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/gruntjs-maximum-call-stack-size-exceeded-error.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>gruntjs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Record your screen in animated GIF format with Licecap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m often being asked what screen recorder software I use, since I frequently document tutorials, emails, and other user guides with self-explanatory gifs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And since the app I use is 1. open source (hence free), 2. super light, and 3. very easy to use, I thought I would give Licecap the credit it deserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cockos.com/licecap/&quot;&gt;the app’s website&lt;/a&gt;, Licecap is a simple animated screen captures software. It probably has the least sexy logo ever, but the app is just great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Show, don’t tell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You open it, set your width, height, and click on record, and you’re done. Stop it, and you’ll get a nice looped gif file, you’ll be able to paste anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How neat is that?! I had always thought it was for mac only, but it was originally for windows environments, so all of you can have a go at this little app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cockos.com/&quot;&gt;Cockos Incorporated&lt;/a&gt; for this beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/record-screen-animated-gif.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/record-screen-animated-gif.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>apps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Autocomplete file names in Sublime</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Another cool add-on to your Sublime with this great little plugin that allows you to autocomple your file names and speed up your coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use your &lt;a href=&quot;https://packagecontrol.io/&quot;&gt;Package Control&lt;/a&gt; (CMD + SHIFT + P) to install &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BoundInCode/AutoFileName&quot;&gt;AutoFileName&lt;/a&gt; and start playing with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Autocomplete FTW!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick gif to show the plugin’s wonders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://flopreynat.com/img/autofilename.gif&quot; alt=&quot;AutoFileName&quot; title=&quot;AutoFileName&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Been using for a long time now, but I reckon it hasn’t got the fame it deserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kudos to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/boundincode&quot;&gt;@boundincode&lt;/a&gt; (Liam Cain), the creator behind AutoFileName.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/autocomplete-file-names-sublimetext.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/autocomplete-file-names-sublimetext.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sublime</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Macbook Pro boots to black screen... WTF</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So you boot your macbook pro, and you get… well not much. A black screen staring back at you while you frantically reach for your phone to check possible solutions to this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pram-reset&quot;&gt;PRAM Reset&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look no further. The thing just happened to me and I managed to get through it by resetting the machine’s PRAM, which is - apparently -  a common troubleshooting technique when your favorite apple goes to f***.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It allegedly should be the last resort when this kind of things happen. But as none of the other techniques I managed to find on the net did work, I’m only going to cover this one since, as mentioned above, it did the trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here how it’s gotta be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;CMD + ALT + P + R&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You reboot the mac, and as soon as you hear the boot-up sound, you hold down the magic key combination displayed above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t got the slightest idea what the problem was, and why I had to do this.
But it just does work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/macbook-pro-boots-to-black-screen.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/macbook-pro-boots-to-black-screen.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Move and resize windows with Spectacle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Repositioning and resizing windows isn’t probably the most entertaining subject out there, but as we do those two all day long, let’s talk about it once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember having blogged about this subject on another blog about 3 years ago, and today, I’m finding myself talking about this very same subject to various mac users (since it’s a native feature on windows), having failed to deal with the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;CMD + ALT + LEFT/RIGHT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;spectacle&quot;&gt;Spectacle&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut a long story short. The app is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spectacleapp.com/&quot;&gt;Spectacle&lt;/a&gt;. It’s very cool, simple, non-obtrusive and free.
And I’ve been using it for ever now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once installed, you’ll have to enable access for assistive devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.flopreynat.com/img/spectacle1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Universal Access&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review your shortcuts, change them if you wish, and start getting more productive with your open windows…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.flopreynat.com/img/spectacle2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Spectacle shortcuts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can run the app in the background but I suggest you add it in the status menu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/move-and-resize-windows-with-spectacle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/move-and-resize-windows-with-spectacle.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Sublime Text Shortcuts CheatSheet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Have you documented your own Sublime Text shortcut cheatsheet?’ is a question I never get asked. But despite all your efforts to avoid the subject, here it is. In your face!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is likely to get updated on a regular basis since I tend to learn new stuff every day. See, when you start low, you’re bound to progress more often than never :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we’ve already spoken about &lt;a href=&quot;http://flopreynat.com/blog/sublimetext-clipboard-history.html&quot;&gt;ST3’s clipboard history capability&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s the rest of the stuff I use on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
	&lt;tbody&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + click&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Multiple cursors&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + C/V&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;(without selecting something) Copy/paste entire line&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + O/S/W&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Open/Save/Close file&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + Control + P&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Get List of Saved Projects&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + X&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Cut Line&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + D&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Grab similar occurences&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + Control + G&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Grab all occurences&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + Shift + F&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Find stuff through files &amp;amp; folders&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + K B&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Toggle sidebar&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + K L&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Go Lower case&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + K U&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Go Upper case&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + Shift + /&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Commenting/Uncommenting&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + Control + up/down&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Swap line order&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Alt + drag&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Initial a column select&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + Shift + left/right&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Select content from cursor to left/right end&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Control + Shift + W&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Wrap Line or Selection with Tag (absolute favourite)&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Command + Control + Shift +F&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Enjoy Distraction-free fullscreen&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Select + [/(&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Wrap selection between parenthesis/brackets&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come obviously…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ps: get yourself a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/buy&quot;&gt;licence&lt;/a&gt;, it’s only 70 box.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/sublime-text-shortcuts-cheatsheet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/sublime-text-shortcuts-cheatsheet.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sublime</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Authenticator is producing the wrong codes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What do you do when your Google Authenticator produces the wrong codes, and there’s nothing much you can do about it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a huge fan of the two-factor authentification, the now famous user identification system by means of the combination of two different components. It usually involves a password and some kind of time-based token available via an app on a mobile phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;2-step verification is officially the best thing since sliced bread&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So by now, we all know we’re talking about Google Authenticator. Great app, I use it all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problem I just encountered: my mobile is in maintenance, and I bought myself a cheap Wiko for the few days/weeks to come, and I can not make the app work. No idea why, the time zone is set as it should, I ran a sync from the app, and it’s telling me that all is fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you do in such a bizarre situation. I found my answer on a forum, but as there’s not so much talk on the subject out there, this blog post may help some people stuck like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use this app: &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.fedorahosted.freeotp&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;FreeOTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems a bit strange to be using a google feature with an app made by Red Hat. But the app is legit and approved, and more importantly it works like a charm, …even on a Wiko.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And get yourself a decent phone though lol.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/google-authenticator-wrong-code.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/google-authenticator-wrong-code.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>google</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Jekyll plugins on Github</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A bit of reading for all jekyll newbies who, like me, decided to host their Jekyll site on Github pages (or are in the process to do so), and wouldn’t be aware of the limitations around the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been running this site on Jekyll for a few weeks only, and making discoveries along the way. When I decided to install and use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/UsabilityEtc/responsive-youtube-jekyll-tag&quot;&gt;the first of many plugins available&lt;/a&gt;, I hit the wall and quickly realised the topic was far from an easy affair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;tl;dr : Avoid using plugins if you can&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to steal the words of David Lyons as he wrote a nicely-documented post on the subjet on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/jekyll-plugins-github/&quot;&gt;sitepoint.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cut a long story short, Github only allows &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/using-jekyll-plugins-with-github-pages/&quot;&gt;a few Jekyll plugins&lt;/a&gt; to run during build process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As David mentioned it, you’ll have a couple of work-arounds to get by.
I personnaly decided not to go with any of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, the current (folder/git) structure setup suits me and I didn’t want to disturb it. Second of all, I don’t have the intention to add a million plugins (as in I intend to use none of them). Lastly, I am the only person operating this site and thought a bit of markup within the post would not be the end of the world, should I need to add a responsive-ready video container (&lt;em&gt;reminder: it’s what I wanted to do in the first place&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, once again, read David’s post. It’s worth a look (and a thought) if you intend to host your Jekyll site on Github pages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/jekyll-plugins-github.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/jekyll-plugins-github.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sublime Text 3 Clipboard History</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently moved to Sublime Text 3, having enjoyed several years of cruising on version 2. The latest version is now more than mature (hence my move) and has additional features ST2 was short of. The ability to browse through your clipboard history is defo one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;⌘ + K then ⌘ + V&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s as simple as that, just go ⌘ + K before hitting your usual ⌘ + V and you’ll be able to pick from your latest clipboard entries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is in the video below, made by &lt;a href=&quot;http://wesbos.com/&quot;&gt;Wes Bos&lt;/a&gt;, a web dev recently featured on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://shoptalkshow.com/episodes/176-with-wes-bos/&quot;&gt;ShopTalk show of July 27th&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IaddB_GQ4Ps&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note, if you want to speed up your development, optimize your ST workflows and become a better developer, Wes has released &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublimetextbook.com/&quot;&gt;a book on the subject&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/sublimetext-clipboard-history.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/sublimetext-clipboard-history.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sublime</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
