<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>flopreynat.com</title>
    <description>website for flopreynat</description>
    <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.flopreynat.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 23:38:09 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 23:38:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Responsive email design framework MJML to the test</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Email design is a real pain in the arse. We all know that. Therefore I decided to give &lt;a href=&quot;https://mjml.io/&quot;&gt;mjml&lt;/a&gt; a go. For those who don’t know of mjml.io, it’s a responsive email design framework built by a team of developers at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mailjet.com&quot;&gt;Mailjet&lt;/a&gt;, a competitor of &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchimp.com/&quot;&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of this framework results in the fact that you create something very much close to html, using an MJML markup language, and as mentioned in its detailed documentation, &lt;em&gt;“its semantic syntax makes it easy and straightforward and its rich standard components library speeds up your development time and lightens your email codebase.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MJML’s open-source engine, which is - by the way - written in &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/en/&quot;&gt;NodeJS&lt;/a&gt; (hence easily installed via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/mjml&quot;&gt;npm&lt;/a&gt;), leverages ReactJS and takes your mjml email designs to process high quality responsive HTML compliant with best practices. That’s the whole idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Easy and quick, Responsive, Component based&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I had nothing much to work with for starters, I decided to use somebody else’s work, and picked this beautiful minimalistic &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/shots/1518379-Newsletter&quot;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; (designed by Dmitri Litvinov) I found on dribbble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/mjml-dribbble-model.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;newsletter model&quot; title=&quot;newsletter model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t go into the details of the design process but with the help of the doc, I put all the components together in a matter of minutes, generated the html template using the terminal and the follwowing syntax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot;&gt;
mjml yourfile.mjml
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the final result of my work in both gmail and protonmail. 
Something not only esthetic but fully functional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/mjml-results.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mjml results&quot; title=&quot;mjml results&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;verdict&quot;&gt;Verdict&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re willing to send what looks like a professional responsive email, without having to use a third-party design service, then I defo advise you to give mjml a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So long.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/responsive-email-design-framework-mjml.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/responsive-email-design-framework-mjml.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>email</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DuckDuckGo hacks for developers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;DuckDuckGo is by far the best search engine out there. For your own privacy for starters, and also as a great little tool for us dev folks, adept of quick tech &amp;amp; code answers, and geeky little features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Smarter Search!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few tips and tricks that you may not know of. I’ve been using some for few for months, and only discovered others in the last few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;navigation&quot;&gt;Navigation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigate through search results using Vim Line Navigation
k – navigate upwards
j – navigate downwards&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/duckduckgo-navigation.gif&quot; alt=&quot;duckduckgo navigation&quot; title=&quot;duckduckgo navigation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cheatsheets&quot;&gt;Cheatsheets&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DuckDuckGo offers a wide range of cheatsheets. Try them out. Just type the language, app, or software of your choice + cheatsheet.
e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=jquery+cheatsheet&amp;amp;t=ffab&amp;amp;ia=cheatsheet&quot;&gt;“jquery cheatsheet”&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=css+cheatsheet&amp;amp;t=ffab&amp;amp;ia=cheatsheet&quot;&gt;“css cheatsheet”&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=javascript+cheatsheet&amp;amp;t=ffab&amp;amp;ia=cheatsheet&quot;&gt;“javascript cheatsheet”&lt;/a&gt;, etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/duckduckgo-cheatsheet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;duckduckgo cheatsheet&quot; title=&quot;duckduckgo cheatsheet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;validators-converters-and-beautifiers&quot;&gt;Validators, converters and beautifiers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=json+validation&amp;amp;ia=answer&quot;&gt;“JSON Beautifier &amp;amp; Validator”&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=HTML+beautifier&amp;amp;ia=answer&quot;&gt;“HTML beautifier”&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=sass+to+css&amp;amp;ia=answer&quot;&gt;“Sass to Css Converter”&lt;/a&gt;, and more…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/duckduckgo-json-validation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;duckduckgo json validation&quot; title=&quot;duckduckgo json validation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;colors&quot;&gt;Colors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=color+picker&amp;amp;ia=answer&quot;&gt;“Color picker”&lt;/a&gt; with RGB, HSV, CMYK conversion and &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=%23000000&amp;amp;ia=answer&quot;&gt;“Hex code converter”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/duckduckgo-color.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;duckduckgo color&quot; title=&quot;duckduckgo color&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;qa&quot;&gt;Q/A&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…on coding questions like &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=how+to+select+img+with+jquery&amp;amp;ia=qa&quot;&gt;“how to select img with jquery”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/duckduckgo-qa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;duckduckgo q&amp;amp;a&quot; title=&quot;duckduckgo q&amp;amp;a&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bangs&quot;&gt;Bangs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to look for something on a specific site, like Stack Overflow (!stack + query) or CSS-Tricks (!csstricks + query). The list of bangs is &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/bang&quot;&gt;“here”&lt;/a&gt;.
Here’s a cool one you can try yourselves: &lt;a href=&quot;!caniuse flexbox&quot;&gt;“!caniuse flexbox”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/duckduckgo-bangs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;duckduckgo bangs&quot; title=&quot;duckduckgo bangs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/duckduckgo-hacks-for-developers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/duckduckgo-hacks-for-developers.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>search</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Personal Data Privacy: start off 2017 on the right foot</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New year new start&lt;/strong&gt;. What a great opportunity to start it off on the right foot and greatly improve your behaviour and overall awareness on the personal data privacy subject. You will feel great and you will start breaking the chain!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As discussed last time &lt;a href=&quot;http://flopreynat.com/blog/data-privacy-matters.html&quot;&gt;we talked on the matter&lt;/a&gt;, our personal data privacy matters a lot, and yet, it is being violated more and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick glimpse at the news tell us &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.androidauthority.com/prime-minister-mays-surveillance-law-729874/&quot;&gt;the UK and Theresa May are trying to pass a law&lt;/a&gt; that will make it obligatory for internet providers to store every user’s history for up to a year (although &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf?text=&amp;amp;docid=186492&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=EN&amp;amp;mode=req&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=516300&quot;&gt;the text has just been declared unlawful by EU’s Highest Court&lt;/a&gt;), or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://netzpolitik.org/2016/projekt-aniski-wie-der-bnd-mit-150-millionen-euro-messenger-wie-whatsapp-entschluesseln-will&quot;&gt;German secret services are allegedly wanting to decrypt messengers like WhatsApp&lt;/a&gt; via the ANISKI project. 
Mass surveillance is a hot topic, and defo on the rise these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;big-deal-i-have-nothing-to-hide&quot;&gt;Big Deal, I have nothing to hide.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Killing the ‘nothing to hide’ argument is probably the easiest thing in the world, so try it yourselves (just for fun) if an idiot tells you he/she has nothing to hide, with this set of decent questions/requests I heard a few folks suggest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Why the fuck do you have curtains in your house?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Hand me all your passwords if you have fuck all to hide then.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Give me your bank receipts of last year, since there’s nothing spectacular in there.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bottom line is: I don’t have anything to hide. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;But I don’t have anything I feel like showing you, either.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-why-is-mass-surveillance-wrong&quot;&gt;So Why is Mass Surveillance wrong?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it invades our private life space&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we have absolutely no control of what is being recorded&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;nor how long it is being stored&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it might not reflect reality&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it might reflect the reality and we might not want to let people know things&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it inhibits free speech&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it inhibits free association&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it puts free press in real danger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it kills creativity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;it has yet to be proved successful in the fight against terrorism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-thing-is-this-is-far-from-new&quot;&gt;The thing is, …this is far from new.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As discussed in this series’ first post, people farming, or automated data processing by the likes of facebook, google and the rest is not only something we signed for (by agreeing to the unread and unreadable services’ terms and conditions), but something we have absolutely accepted as THE standard web app model. As in free but far from private.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples are countless, but to name only one, feel free to check &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uber.com/legal/terms/us/&quot;&gt;Über’s latest terms of use update&lt;/a&gt;, where you grant Über a worldwide, perpetual, irrevocable, transferable, royalty-free license, with the right to sublicense, to use, copy, modify, create derivative works of, distribute, publicly display, publicly perform, and otherwise exploit in any manner any User Content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about Big Brothers, you will also enjoy those quotes from a Google executive, stating &lt;em&gt;“Google policy is to get right up to the creepy line and not cross it”&lt;/em&gt;, or even &lt;em&gt;“With your permission you give us more information about you, about your friends, and we can improve the quality of our searches […] We don’t need you to type at all.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, and as stated in a court filing, &lt;em&gt;“all users of email must necessarily expect that their emails will be subject to automated processing. Just as a sender of a letter to a business colleague cannot be surprised that the recipient’s assistant opens the letter, people who use web-based email today cannot be surprised if their emails are processed by the recipient’s [email provider] in the course of delivery.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, so Google is kind of reading your emails, facebook is recording everything you do/post/interact with for ever, and even if you don’t use those services, you are being followed by countless trackers anywhere you go on the web. Not aware of this? Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://donottrack-doc.com/en/&quot;&gt;Do not track series&lt;/a&gt;, they surely will entertain you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So…
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;any-solutions-out-there&quot;&gt;Any solutions out there?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As clearly stated by Aral Balkan in &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/190855745&quot;&gt;his talk&lt;/a&gt;, regulation, legislation, and ethical design are indeed the answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But while waiting for our constitution reps to dump lobbyists and defend our digital rights, let’s do our part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let’s do our part and break the chain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not use Facebook/Gmail/etc… if you can&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you can’t, Do not put your whole life on Facebook, Twitter, etc…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt; as default search engine, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/privacy&quot;&gt;they don’t track you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Block laptop camera + laptop microphone if you are not using them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn off location on your mobile phone as much as you can&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn off your phone at night&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/&quot;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; as much as you can on your desktop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orbot/&quot;&gt;Orbot&lt;/a&gt; (and hence Orfox) as much as you can on your android if you have one&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you don’t have enough patience, use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/&quot;&gt;Mozilla’s Firefox&lt;/a&gt; as default browser. Ok they get funded by the other big guns I’m talking about (as they need mozilla’s search traffic). But they’re non profit, big on privacy and encryption, so let’s give them credit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Block trackers (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ind.ie/&quot;&gt;Better from Indie&lt;/a&gt; for Safari, &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/ublock-origin/&quot;&gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/fr/firefox/addon/ghostery/&quot;&gt;Ghostery&lt;/a&gt;… although I’m hearing things about Ghostery selling their stats back)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/&quot;&gt;Protonmail&lt;/a&gt; account ffs! Paying a small amount for private email is good for you, and a very decent model&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://spideroak.com/&quot;&gt;Spideroak&lt;/a&gt; for cloud storage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Signal from &lt;a href=&quot;https://whispersystems.org&quot;&gt;Open Whisper Systems&lt;/a&gt; for encrypted text messaging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://framatalk.org&quot;&gt;Framatalk&lt;/a&gt; or similar tool for video conference&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and probably the most important part of all:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;
PASS THIS BLOODY MESSAGE ONTO YOUR FRIENDS AND RELATIVES !!
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Otherwise, happy new year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Publicly yours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/personal-data-privacy-in-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/personal-data-privacy-in-2017.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Create a PDF Compress Automator App</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Every time I want to compress pdfs on a new apple machine, I find myself looking for the same (great) posts on the subject, and rarely find the one I’m looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I’m putting up this nice (personal) go-to blog post on how to easily and quickly set up a PDF Compress Automator App, as I use the app almost every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;small is beautiful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right so, the steps are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Download the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joshcarr/Apple-Quartz-Filters&quot;&gt;Apple Quartz filters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Move the filters to your ~/Library/ folder by launching Finder and using CMD + SHIFT + G to pull up the Go to access Library folder, and dropping a “Filters” folder containing the quartz filters in there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Launch Automator and Create an Application by dragging the Apply Quartz Filter to PDF Documents from left to right, and set the desired options (eg Reduce to 150 dpi average quality - STANDARD COMPRESSION) before giving it a name (save it onto your desktop).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now drag your pdf to your newly-created PDF Compress Application, and you’ll get a fresh copy reduced in size (obviously)…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/pdf-compress-automator-app.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/pdf-compress-automator-app.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tools</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>(Our Personal) Data Privacy Matters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;(Our personal) Data Privacy is a big deal. If you, like me, get annoyed every time you receive an unwanted newsletter, or feel wary about looking up some specific items while logged in on google, you’ll know what I’m talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This subject has always been of great interest to me, both from personal and technoligcal stand points.
And as time passes by, and I see new generations of youngsters come into play, with absolutely no experience of what the time without the internet could have looked/felt like, it gets me thinking more and more about this situation, which I know isn’t new, but is not getting any better to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the reason why I am launching today with this quick post a series of articles on the subject.
I have made drastic changes in my personal life theses last few weeks, and this blog is a great way to keep the words of advice from all savvy people resonate, and share my actions and overall experience in improving my personal data privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with a cool prez from &lt;a href=&quot;https://ar.al/&quot;&gt;Aral Balkan&lt;/a&gt; who’s taken his &lt;a href=&quot;https://ind.ie/beyond-the-clouds/&quot;&gt;Beyond The Clouds&lt;/a&gt; prez to another level with ‘The Matrix, Inverted’, a great talk on people faming made in Malmö, at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://oredev.org/&quot;&gt;Øredev Conference&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If it’s free, YOU are the product&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For your info, I have been following Aral’s work for a few years now. Aral is big on Human Rights, Social Justice &amp;amp; Ethical Design, and runs &lt;a href=&quot;https://ind.ie/&quot;&gt;ind.ie&lt;/a&gt;, a small social enterprise striving for social justice in the digital age.
His eloquence and passion for defending data privacy are second to none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the wise words!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/190855745&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/190855745&quot;&gt;The Matrix, Inverted&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/user4280938&quot;&gt;&amp;Oslash;redev Conference&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/data-privacy-matters.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/data-privacy-matters.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Speed up your Salesforce admin search with Sid&#39;s Searchbox</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re a Salesforce user, especially a developer or admin, you may spend most of your day in the Salesforce setup area, adding and editing apex classes, visualforce pages and adjusting other admin settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything helping you stop wasting time on the setup area is more than welcome. Therefore I can only recommend you to give this chrome extension a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In Search of Speed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Made by Salesforce MVP and Dreamforce 16 superstar ;) Sid Nagavarapu, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/salesforce-searchbox/moaokcjghnjifeeahifofckbmhofjdbi&quot;&gt;“Salesforce Searchbox”&lt;/a&gt; is a great way to gain in productivity by adding to all config pages a simple search box, which will search in all configuration items on the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/salesforce-admin-search-account.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;salesforce search admin&quot; title=&quot;salesforce search admin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plugin supports some basic regex searches if you want to go fancy. In any case, you’ll speed up your searches and will defo spend more time providing the most value to the CRM users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/salesforce-admin-search.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/salesforce-admin-search.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>salesforce</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RSI and vertical mouse: a look back at the last 6 months</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Repetitive strain injury (RSI) is a frequent issue when you spend 10+ hours a day in front of a computer, and it is something I have unfortunately been experiencing these last few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I own a mac, I have always been using a magic mouse, but as aching in my right hand (and arm) started to occur on a more regular basis, I started wondering whether this beautiful, yet - let’s be honest - way too small device was the root of my problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;DANGER MOUSE !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discussing the matter with my osteopath quickly led to the option of using a vertical mouse, helping you  keep your hand in a natural position. This is why I moved to ‘verticality’ 6 months ago, with the purchase of a basic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.fr/gp/product/B00D84P8O8/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o07_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;“usb vertical mouse ZeleSouris”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few reasons why I picked this low-budget mouse:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;this was going to be more like a pilot phase (so I thought)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;non-wireless mice are less heavy (no batteries), hence easier to move&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;this specific device was not pricy hence more than worth a shot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 months on and I have to admit this was the best choice ever. Getting used to it took only a few days as far as I was concerned. I doubt the mouse I picked is the best ever, but my RSI has gone for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can only advise you to ditch the good looks of the magic mouse for an old bulky mouse, a trackpad or a vertical mouse, should you suffer (or wish to prevent) from RSI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/rsi-vertical-mouse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/rsi-vertical-mouse.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>uncategorized</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wordpress staging environments on the cheap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Staging environments are one of the keys of a (proper and) controlled deployment process, whatever the technology. Wordpress isn’t any different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have a problem if you - like me - run a few things on wordpress, don’t consider it as a priority subject (hence do not have the time, nor the money to commit on the suject), …yet still want to make it a decent process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typical “have it both ways” conundrum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;DEV &amp;gt; STAGING ENVIRONMENT &amp;gt; PRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here are a few options, my views on them, and eventually a decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professional Wordpress hosting (Paid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best option is to get people (or an app) meant to do this for you. Defo the best option if this subject is top priority for you. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wpengine.com/support/staging/&quot;&gt;“WPEngine”&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://mediatemple.net/community/products/wordpress/204645480/staging-sites-for-your-wordpress-hosting-service&quot;&gt;“Media Temple”&lt;/a&gt; come to mind to name only a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WP Migrate DB Pro (Paid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A popular plugin, often praised on &lt;a href=&quot;http://shoptalkshow.com/&quot;&gt;“ShopTalk Show”&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://deliciousbrains.com/wp-migrate-db-pro/pricing/&quot;&gt;“WP Migrate DB Pro”&lt;/a&gt; is a great option to get your wordpress sites in sync (all content including media) with one click. Cool option to implement a push to production process. Starting at 89 box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: I ain’t being sponsored for any of those paid options.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, I can’t be investigating any resource in this subject. Yet, I want to be able to set up a few environments and sync content and settings in an easy (and quick process), without having to deal with media url issues (cough wordpress import cough).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me emphasize on the repeatable process here since I really want to be able to do more than the usual local wp-cloud wp sync’ing. Testing things as they live on the web has got to be a pre-requisite. Things happen differently when not happening on local machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, went with…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All-in-One WP Migration (Free)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As advertised, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/all-in-one-wp-migration/&quot;&gt;“the plugin”&lt;/a&gt; allows you to export your database, media files, plugins, and themes. You can apply unlimited find/replace operations on your database and the plugin will also fix any serialization problems that occur during find/replace operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not bad for a free option, and works like a charm to get those wordpress environments in sync.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/wordpress-staging-environment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/wordpress-staging-environment.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>wordpress</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Create a dribbble API-powered portfolio in no time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;APIs are a foundational element in today’s tech world. They help you enrich your data, and remain the best, simplest and quickest way to integrate to other engines, apps … you name it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example, we’ll focus on a quick (and dirty) dribble to website integration, helping you generate a dribbble-api-powered portfolio, and kill two birds with one stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Leveraging APIs Matters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick (code)pen below showing you in details how I did it.
Do not be too judgemental on the overall design, this was made in a few minutes, throwing bootstrap on a page before connecting to my dribbble account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The longest part was to register an application on your dribbble account. Simply log into your account, navigate to Account Settings &amp;gt; Applications, and register your app. You’ll be needing your Client Access Token to make this work…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;265&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;0&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;oLgyZQ&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;js,result&quot; data-user=&quot;flopreynat&quot; data-embed-version=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/flopreynat/pen/oLgyZQ/&quot;&gt;dribbble portfolio with dribbble api v1&lt;/a&gt; by flo preynat (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/flopreynat&quot;&gt;@flopreynat&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/dribbble-api-portfolio.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/dribbble-api-portfolio.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mac Finder freezes... WTF</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Another blog post on Apple devices playing up (following the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flopreynat.com/blog/macbook-pro-boots-to-black-screen.html&quot;&gt;“boot to black screen”&lt;/a&gt; one) with this time, the way to resolve a frozen finder on OSX (Mavericks in my case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing happened to me a few months back, with Finder freezing over and over after a few seconds or minutes of usage, forcing me to force quit Finder on numerous occasions throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fed up with this bug, and not willing to move away from the native file managing app, I eventually got it sorted out by simply using Mac’s Safe Mode, something that Windows users might be more inclined to be using on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Safe Mode baby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personnally had never used the safe mode before, despite around 10 years on apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you have a frozen Finder, go for it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow these steps to start up into safe mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start or restart your Mac.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Immediately after you hear the startup sound, press and hold the Shift key.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release the Shift key when you see the Apple logo appear on the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Apple logo appears, it might take longer than usual to reach the login screen or your desktop. This is because your Mac performs a directory check of your startup disk as part of safe mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To leave safe mode, restart your computer without pressing any keys during startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201262&quot;&gt;“Apple Support website”&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/mac-finder-freezes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.flopreynat.com/blog/mac-finder-freezes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
